Guide to the Stuart Sherman Papers 1945-2001 (Bulk 1961-2001) MSS 192
© 2009 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IX: Video
  - Subseries B: Video Recordings - Originals
    - "Christmas Spectacle", 12/9/94, 1994 (Folder ID: 192.0046)
    - "X Mas Spectacle", [1994] (Folder ID: 192.0081)
    - "Perfilmance" at Anthology, 11/5/94, 1994 (Folder ID: 192.0074)
    - "Perfilmance", [1994] (Folder ID: 192.0012)
      TRT: [01:02:00]
    - "Perfilmance", [1994] (Folder ID: 192.0026)
    - Dixon Place, 9/10/94, 1994 (Folder ID: 192.0088)
    - Fondation Cartier, Seirees nomades ete 1994 (Folder ID: 192.0118)
      TRT: [00:50:00]
    - Selections - "The Eighteenth Spectacle - The Spaghetti Works", Fond Cartier, Paris, 1994 (Folder ID: 192.0123)
    - 9/17/1994 (Folder ID: 192.0173)
    - La MaMa - Musical, 1/10/94, 1994 (Folder ID: 192.0176)
    - 9/16/1994 (Folder ID: 192.0179)
    - 5/14/1994 (Folder ID: 192.0184)
    - 12/10/1994 (Folder ID: 192.0190)
    - "Pull (A Portrait of David Nunemaker)", 1994 (Folder ID: 192.0191)
      TRT: 12:04:00
    - "Pull (A Portrait of David Nunemaker)", [1994] (Folder ID: 192.0044)
    - "Me and Joe", [1994] (Folder ID: 192.0016)
      TRT: [00:04:00]
    - "Holy Bible", "Ah-Choo!", [1994] (Folder ID: 192.0186)
    - "Black Eyed Susan", La MaMa - Bill Rice, Stuart Sherman, 2/6/95, 1995 (Folder ID: 192.0174)
    - Amsterdam - Tape 1, 1995 (Folder ID: 192.0178)
    - 5/29/1995 (Folder ID: 192.0185)
    - George and Sherman, 5/30/95, 1995 (Folder ID: 192.0187)
    - ["Spectacle"] 6/17/97 [?], [1997] (Folder ID: 192.0079)
    - Tape 3, "Eyes", undated (Folder ID: 192.0052)
    - George Ashley; Taxi Dance Performance; [illegible words] "Chekhov", undated (Folder ID: 192.0001)
    - N/A, undated (Folder ID: 192.0013)
    - "May Project" by Scorpio, undated (Folder ID: 192.0014)
    - "Protektion" [?] Kurz Film Festival, undated (Folder ID: 192.0020)
    - 8, undated (Folder ID: 192.0022)
    - TV Program interview, undated (Folder ID: 192.0037)
    - Performance, Sherman #2, undated (Folder ID: 192.0039)
    - "…w/ four performers", undated (Folder ID: 192.0040)
    - Performance, 3 Mercer, undated (Folder ID: 192.0042)
    - MOMA [other illegible titles], undated (Folder ID: 192.0048)
    - Tape #1, pre-shoot [unidentified project], undated (Folder ID: 192.0055)
    - "Forest Fire", undated (Folder ID: 192.0057)
    - Tape #1, "SSB, Nancy Tobin, Stalemate, [illegible subtitles], sneezing", undated (Folder ID: 192.0058)
    - Tape #2, pre-shoot, June 12, undated (Folder ID: 192.0059)
    - Stuart Sherman segment from KRMA-TV production of "Season Ticket" [interview], undated (Folder ID: 192.0061)
    - Tape #2, original material - [illegible subtitles] "music/ bulls/ mouse", undated (Folder ID: 192.0063)
    - Stuart [Burbank, Essex ?], undated (Folder ID: 192.0080)
    - "The Gift of Gab", Artists in Residence, by George Kuchar, undated (Folder ID: 192.0084)
    - "An Evening with Stuart Sherman and Students", undated (Folder ID: 192.0094)
    - Stuart Sherman I: Films and Performances, undated (Folder ID: 192.0098)
    - Stuart Sherman, undated (Folder ID: 192.0099)
    - K. Kelman's "Uncle Adolf", undated (Folder ID: 192.0119)
    - Performance selections, undated (Folder ID: 192.0150)
    - "Tower", 9/12, undated (Folder ID: 192.0054)
    - Stuart Sherman?, undated (Folder ID: 192.0171)
    - Subway, undated (Folder ID: 192.0172)
    - Selections - Films and Performances, undated (Folder ID: 192.0102)
    - Stuart Sherman Performance Tape, undated (Folder ID: 192.0008)
    - Stuart Sherman Performance Tape [see 192.0011B for full credit sheet], undated (Folder 192.0011A)
  - Subseries C: Video - Paper Material
    - Performance Tape credit sheet, undated (Box 4, Folder 192.0011B)
      Source: 192.0011A
    - "An Evening of On-Act Plays..." at HOME, program/credit sheet, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 192.0025B)
      Source: 192.0025A
    - "Tape 1, Language [?]", shot index notecards, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 192.0133B)
      Source: 192.0133A
    - "Black-Eyed Susan" screening promo card, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 192.0144B)
      Source: 192.0144A
- Series X: Film
  This series contains the film material from the Stuart Sherman Papers. Researcher access is limited to Subseries A: Film - Access Copies.
  - Subseries A: Film - Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Access copies for film are not presently available. Please contact a Fales Archivist for further information.
  - Subseries B: Film - Originals
    - Boxing footage, Undated (Folder ID: 192.0195)
      Format: 16mm
    - Stuart Sherman as Robert Beck, Undated (Folder ID: 192.0196)
      Format: 8mm
      TRT: [Unknown]
    - Stuart Sherman, Camera - Marianne and Joel, Undated (Folder ID: 192.0197)
      Format: Super 8mm
    - [untitled], Undated (Folder ID: 192.0214)
- Series XI: Audio
  This series includes audio recordings from the Stuart Sherman Papers. Researcher access is limited to Subseries A - Audio Recordings - Access Copies.
  - Subseries A: Audio Recordings - Access Copies
    Access copies for audio are not presently available. Please contact a Fales Archivist for further information.
  - Subseries B: Audio Recordings - Originals
    - [untitled], undated (Folder ID: 192.0198)
      Format: 1/4" audiotape TRT: [Unknown]
    - 4 Sound Pieces; Telephone, undated (Folder ID: 192.0199)
      Format: 1/4" audiotape
    - Telephone, undated (Folder ID: 192.0200)
    - 4 Sound Pieces (Doors, Water, "Click", Pinball) + Brecht, undated (Folder ID: 192.0201)
    - Tony - Reaction II Flint; Strinberg, 1986 (Folder ID: 192.0202)
    - [untitled], undated (Folder ID: 192.0203)
    - [untitled], undated (Folder ID: 192.0204)
    - 3 Sound Pieces, undated (Folder ID: 192.0205)
    - [untitled], undated (Folder ID: 192.0206)
    - Atelier de Creation Radiophonique (Rene Farabet), Sherman, undated (Folder ID: 192.0207)
    - Radio France - Stuart Sherman, undated (Folder ID: 192.0208)
    - [untitled], undated (Folder ID: 192.0209)
    - 4 Sound Pieces, undated (Folder ID: 192.0210)
      Format: audiocassette
    - Sherman - ACR '93 (Atelier de …), 1993 (Folder ID: 192.0211)
    - [untitled], undated (Folder ID: 192.0212)
    - [untitled], undated (Folder ID: 192.0213)
    - [untitled], undated (Folder ID: 192.0214)
  - Subseries C: Audio - Works by Others
    - Ancient Echoes - Chorovaya Akademia, Alexander Sedov (BMG, 1995) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0224)
      Format: compact disc
      TRT: 00:63:25
    - Satie, The Early Piano Works 2-disc (Philips, 1998) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0225)
      TRT: 02:22:39
    - Ethel Merman in Annie Get Your Gun cast album (RCA Victor, 1988) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0226)
      TRT: 00:50:42
    - The Mystery of Santo Domingo de Silos, Gregorian Chant From Spain (Deutsche Grammaphon, 1969) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0227)
    - Moments of Pleasure single, Kate Bush (EMI, 1993) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0228)
    - Japanese pop recording (Columbia Japan, 1986) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0229)
      TRT: 00:70:54
    - Charles Tenet (EMI, 1980) (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0230)
    - "Olde Christmas Caroles", Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0231)
    - Christmas in Choir, The Monastic Choir, The Abbey of the Genesee, Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0232)
    - "Past 3 O'clock", Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0233)
    - "Past 3 O'clock" copy, Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0234)
    - "The Hustle" (loop), Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0235)
    - "Sukiyaki", Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0236)
    - London Cast, High Spirit, Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0237)
    - Virgil Thompson, Mostly About Love, Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0238)
    - Ivor Cutler, "Dandruff", Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0239)
    - Kyu Sakamoto - Sukiyaki, Tankobushi 45 rpm (Capitol Records), Undated (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0240)
      Format: vinyl recording
    - Stefan Brecht, Poems, 33 rpm, 1976 (Box 9, Folder ID: 192.0241)
- Series XII: Misc. Media
  This series contains all digital media files.
  - Digital Files - Stuart Sherman, "Uncle Adolph" (revised); 12/30/00, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    Format: 3.5" diskette
  - Digital Files - Stuart Sherman, "Me+You (1+2)" [other unidentified works], 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Digital Files - Stuart Sherman, "The Stations (requirements)" [and other works], 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Digital Files - "thbible", wp versions [?], undated (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Digital Files - Books [?], undated (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Misc. 5.25" diskettes, undated (Box 4, Folder 136)
    Format: 5.25" diskettes
- Series XIII: Objects
  This series contains all objects. Several objects could not be kept in the collection due to irreparable water damage and/or excessive mold including one Sony Walkman, one bag of multi-colored balloons, two black gloves, two black shoes, and several other articles of clothing.
  - Water gun umbrella ("Disparaguas - Empapate de Alegria"), undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0001)
  - Black mask, undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0002)
  - Plastic frames (circular glasses), undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0003)
  - AIDS ribbon, undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0004)
  - Pin of juggler (from Lyppens and Schipper, Amsterdam), undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0005)
  - Personal movie viewer with two Stuart Sherman film cartridges (in decorated box), undated (Box 10, Folder 192.2.0006)
- Oversize Series
  This series contains oversize materials from Series IV, VII and includes one performance poster and misc. oversize artworks. Series IV: Performance Series VI: Artworks
  - Series IV: Performance
    - Poster - "Stuart Sherman Taal Uilenspiegel" Euro. Performance Tour, 1990-1991 (Box 11 (oversize box), Folder 137)
  - Series VI: Artworks
    - Drafts - Set/ Stage Design [2 color copies], undated (Box 11 (oversize box), Folder 138)
    - Drafts - Sculpture [6 color copies], 1987, undated (Box 11 (oversize box), Folder 139)
    - Original Drafts - Sculpture [12], 1985-1992 (Box 11 (oversize box), Folder 140)
    - Original Drafts - Sculpture [24], undated (Box 11 (oversize box), Folder 141)
    - Collage works [12], 1995-1996 (Box 11 (oversize box), Folder 142)
    - Framed Artwork - "Rugged Terrain", 1996 (Box 11 (oversize box), Folder 143)
    - Artwork - misc. Paintings, Collage, etc. [6], N/A (Box 11 (oversize box), Folder 144)